今天我們有領導教會的教會團隊為我們去靜悟
我們邀請教會團隊上來
我們也有多功能的Chapman為我們去做一個即時的傳譯
我們一起去…
我也想多說兩句
其實我們一間教會,一會兩語
很小心
一個教會裡面有兩種語言的崇拜
其實是一個很重要的訊息
那個合一,用這個方式去呈現其實很不容易
我告訴你其實是很難的
我們花很多精神和心機去想
我們怎樣能夠將兩個不同的群體成為一個教會裡面的合一
但是神定義就是要我們不是去做容易的事
我們去做對的事
做祂要我們做的事
所以今天我們也有領導教會和我們分享
他自己心裡面對於整個教會裡面
接下來一年的異象
所以我們也準備好心去聆聽
神怎樣透過這個訊息告訴我們
我們同心為著領導教會和Chapman去祈禱
親愛的天父我們感謝你
我們感謝你讓你的訊息不被任何的語言去阻隔
沒有東西能夠阻隔我們的關係
因為藉著你的靈我們能夠去領受
藉著你的靈我們能夠相通
藉著你的靈我們能夠讓你充滿
明白到你要告訴我們的每一個訊息
所以主要求你去賜福Pastor Tim和Pastor Chapman
當Pastor Tim去準備他的訊息的時候
你的靈已經在他當中
所以主要求你讓我們靈相通的時候
我們能夠去領受到你今天要告訴我們的
所有的話語所有的訊息
讓我們能夠明瞭
讓我們能夠知道我們怎樣去實踐出來
我們禱告奉教主耶穌基督的名
Amen
Thank you Pastor Ivan
生日快樂
生日健康
事事如意
(掌聲)
That's it
就是這麼多了
You know it is so incredible to see you
今年可以在這裡見到大家實在太好了
Cause you are God's dream come true
因為你們每一個都是神的夢想成真
Cause God placed this dream in our heart
The planted church with an English and a Cantonese service
神將一個夢想放在我們裡面
要去藉一間相遇的教會
And it's amazing to see it happen
現在可以見到這件事終於發生
真是非常之驚歎令我們
So you are God's dream come true
你們每一個都是神的夢想在這裡成真
Now as we stand at the beginning of 2024 as Divine in Long
當我們作為元朗的葡萄藤教會
來到站立在2024年開始的時候
We want to take some time and look back at last year
我們想花點時間去看一看去年
In order for us to move forward
以致我們可以繼續向前
What God has for us in 2024
去知道神有什麼已經為我們預備了去經歷在2024年
God has been incredible and faithful and so good to us
神是非常非常信實和對我們很好
So I want to share with you some highlights from last year
所以我想分享去年幾個精華的片段
In January we moved as a launch team
from Wan Chai to Yuen Long and started our English service
上年我們作為一個一開始的小組
由灣仔搬來元朗那裏正式開始
At EIS we went from being acquaintances who knew each other
我們在EIS那裏由我們大家一場相識
To becoming a spiritual family that knows each other
That knows what's going on in each other's lives
That loves each other deeply
我們慢慢變成了一個熟人的家庭
我們開始彼此認識
知道大家的生命裏面發生著什麼
We went from being a launch team to being a local church
我們由一個開始去直堂的團隊
變成了一間地方的教會
During the summer we had our first child dedication
Baptisms and we started live preaching
在暑假的時候我們有我們第一個英雄的奉獻禮
然後我們有我們的浸禮
而且還開始了我們自己去現場講道
And then on August 20th
We launched our Cantonese service
然後我們之後還開始了我們廣東話的崇拜
以致我們可以歡迎更多人來到我們的家庭裏面
Pastor Ivan 他的團隊做得非常非常之好
因為要在一間英文的教會裏面開一個廣東話崇拜其實很不容易
所以我們感謝主
Now in September we moved into this venue here
我們在上年九月搬進來這個地方
And on October 1st we had our public launch
我們在十月一日有個正式的開幕
And God did so much to make this happen
神幕後做了很多事讓這件事可以發生得到
So since we moved in here
由我們搬進來之後
We had Alpha in Cantonese and English
我們有中英文的啟發
And we started partnering with NGOs like YWAM Shanty, YWAM Harbour City
Branches of Hope, Oasis and also EIS
我們就跟很多不同的機構合作
We also went from initially having 35 people that stepped out from one child to plant this church
我們剛剛在灣仔開始的時候
團隊有35個人
To having 166 adults and 31 children on average every Sunday
現在我們每個星期大約有160多個大人
還有30多個小朋友
And we were also able by God's grace to establish 8 community groups
Where people can grow spiritually, be encouraged and find support
而且我們有8個小組
大家可以在那裏找到他們屬靈的支援
和有人跟他們同行
So God has been so faithful
他在我們中間是很信實
He has been so good
他在我們中間真的非常之好
But here we stand at the beginning of 2024
但我們現在站立在2024年開始的這一刻
And there is still a lot that God is inviting us into
神仍然邀請我們進入
有很多很多的東西在等著我們
So part of our vision of planting this church
在我們去植這間堂的時候
其中一部分的意象
Has always been to love and serve the Yuen Long community
就是很想去愛去服侍在元朗這裏本地的群體
In practical and impactful ways
是去一些很實際
而且可以帶有影響力的方法來對它做
And this year we see ourselves especially serving
ethnic minority families
and ethnic majority families
我們見到在我們中間
我們服侍到一些少數族裔
而且也有一些可能是我們很多本地的家庭
But here is the thing
但要說的是
We know we cannot do this out of our own strength
我們知道我們不可以靠自己的能力去做這件事
We need the Holy Spirit to work in our lives
我們需要聖靈在我們生命裏面去工作
We need the wisdom
我們需要祂的智慧
And we need the Holy Spirit to prepare us
我們需要聖靈來預備我們
To equip us
來裝備我們
To unite us
來叫我們團結
To lead us
來帶領我們
To empower us
來給我們力量
For the ministry and the work that He is calling us to do in this place
為了祂在這個地方裏面要叫我們去做的侍奉
我們要去預備我們
And so we are beginning the year with a 21-day fast
所以我們今年用一個21天的禁食來開始
And the fast is going to start tomorrow
January 8th to January 28th
這個禁食由明天1月8日開始
一直到1月28日
And that's something that we do every year as the Divine Church
作為葡萄藤教會其實我們每一年都做這件事
To prepare ourselves what God has for us
來預備神要放在我們裏面的東西
And we step into the destiny, the mission and the purpose of God in 2024
讓我們可以踏進在2024年裏面
神給我們的命定,使命和任務
And so for me when I think of this
I have this image of us just falling on our knees
And crying out to God saying
Lord we need you, we cannot do this out of our own strength
當我想像這件事的時候
我腦海裏面見到一個圖畫
就是我們一起去跪下向神去呼求
神啊你一定要來幫我們,教我們怎樣做
我們自己用自己的能力做不到
And we long for a move of the Holy Spirit
我們很渴望聖靈的大能去運行
To do a work in our hearts
來到在我們的心裏面去工作
To then move out
然後我們一起出去
Because we cannot do it out of our own strength
因為我們不可以靠自己的力量去做
I cannot motivate you to do it
我不可以叫你,推你去做
But it's the work of God in our lives
That drives us and mobilizes us and leads us into His work
而是神在我們的生命裏面去驅動我們
來鼓勵我們一起完成祂的工作
So that is my prayer for this fast
所以這個就是我為我們禁食的禱告
That the Holy Spirit works in our lives
聖靈會在我們的生命裏面工作
And moves us out in love
來叫我們一起出去,去到外
And moves us out in the power of His Spirit
一起在祂的能力裏面,在聖靈的大能裏面
一起來出去
So we are not relying on our own strength
所以我們不是靠自己的力量
We are not relying on our own wisdom
不是只靠自己的智慧
But on the power of God
而是靠著神的大能
So we are not relying on our own strength
We are relying on our own power
So we are not relying on our own power
So we are not relying on our own strength
So today our topic is fasting
We are doing what is known as a corporate fast
But besides that, I believe
that God is inviting us into a personal fast as well at the same time
So I want to encourage you to ask the Holy Spirit
what He wants you to fast about
Is there a relationship to fast about?
Is there a need for guidance to fast about?
Is there a recurring struggle with sin
that we need broken in our lives, this pattern of sin
Is there an area where we need favor and provision?